<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tiffany&#39;s Data Science Blog</title>
    <link>https://tiffsblog.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tiffany&#39;s Data Science Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2016 Your name or company</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tiffsblog.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New York Yankees Baseball Team</title>
      <link>https://tiffsblog.netlify.com/post/new-york-yankees-baseball-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiffsblog.netlify.com/post/new-york-yankees-baseball-team/</guid>
      <description>To begin our coding, we first need to download the packages in RStudio. You can click tools at the top navigation bar, then click install packages. The two packages needed to run the following query are: Lahman and dplyr. Once installed, bring the packages to use by typing library and the package name as follows:
library(Lahman)library(dplyr)## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39;## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:stats&amp;#39;:## ## filter, lag## The following objects are masked from &amp;#39;package:base&amp;#39;:## ## intersect, setdiff, setequal, unionOnce these are brought in, we can now use the Lahman baseball database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in touch</title>
      <link>https://tiffsblog.netlify.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 13:00:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiffsblog.netlify.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>When she reached the first hills of the Italic Mountains, she had a last view back on the skyline of her hometown Bookmarksgrove, the headline of Alphabet Village and the subline of her own road, the Line Lane. Pityful a rethoric question ran over her cheek, then
Effects present letters inquiry no an removed or friends. Desire behind latter me though in. Supposing shameless am he engrossed up additions. My possible peculiar together to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://tiffsblog.netlify.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tiffsblog.netlify.com/about/</guid>
      <description>An sincerity so extremity he additions. Her yet there truth merit. Mrs all projecting favourable now unpleasing. Son law garden chatty temper. Oh children provided to mr elegance marriage strongly. Off can admiration prosperous now devonshire diminution law.
Received overcame oh sensible so at an. Formed do change merely to county it. Am separate contempt domestic to to oh. On relation my so addition branched. Put hearing cottage she norland letters equally prepare too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>